Yogini Shimpi

♥ Mumbai, Maharashtra, India 🛥 shimpiyoginio2@gmail.com 🗖 (+91)7841815771

SUMMARY

In-depth knowledge and experience on major modules of SAP like FI Enterprise Structure, General Ledger, Accounts Receivable, and Accounts Payable. Excellent attention to detail, coupled with strong organizational skills for ensuring a streamlined and efficient payment process. Wish to offer my services to an organization wherein my experience and skills are utilized for the fulfilment of business objectives. Accounting and Finance professional with 6 years of experience in Accounting Operations, SAP End User Operations, Bank/Vendor Reconciliation process. Revised and streamlined inefficient work procedures with the help of respective software.

EXPERIENCE

SAP FICO Consultant

Wipro Limited

25th April 2022— 26th July 2024- July 2024, Thane

- \cdot Worked as a Coordinator for SAP FICO Functional support along with implementation.
- · Managing Remedy tool for raising ticket for SAP FICO.
- · Coordinate Monthly Patching Activity of UAT and Production Server.
- · Daily maintenance of work order Report and co-ordinating same with Fourth Signal (FS Vendor).
- · Reporting related to GL, AR, AP, Tax Reports, Asset report, Cash and Bank report to the Business team as and when required.
- · Maintenance of Email ids for the Scheduled jobs.
- · SAP ID Creation and T code Authorization.
- · Support to Issues on FI New field addition such as Business Area code, Bus.Place Updation, Payment Method Related Issues, etc.
- · Review S2/S3 Documents with Business Team, Testing Documents in UAT and Move the changes into SAP Production System.
- · Implementation/Configuration related Basic Set up of FICO, Enterprise structure, Field Status, posting period, Fiscal Year Variant, COA set up, Document type with number range of FI and CO, maintain Controlling area, Hierarchy for Profit Centre and Cost Centre, Maintain Version for Plan and Actual, with all posting like, Normal GL Posting, Park Documents, Sample document, Reference Document, Recurring document, Hold Document, Create Jobs, Changes Variant and Layouts, Tolerance limit for Employee.
- · Configuration of Vendor and Customer, configuration of BP Role, posting of Vendor and Customer, Tolerance for Customer and Vendor, Customer Invoice, Vendor Invoice, Credit Memo, Incoming & Outgoing Payment (Partial, Residual payment, Standard payment, On Account), Document Splitting, and new GL.
- FI Tax Configuration and also posting, Foreign Currency Postings with configuration set up, APP Configuration with APP Run, House Bank set up, Document Splitting (New GL), Exchange rate set up, with postings, settings for advance to customer and vendor with postings.
- · Master data creation for Customer, Vendor, GL master, Fixed Asset, Cost Center, Profit Center, Fixed Asset Set up configuration with posting related to Fixed Asset Acquisition, Sales of Fixed Asset, Asset under Construction, Settlement of AUC, Depreciation posting, Foreign Currency valuation, Financial Statement Version Creation.
- $\cdot \ \text{FI-CO Integration, Knowledge on topic of FI-MM \& FI-SD Integration knowledge on configuration.}$

Lecturer

Prof. Ramakrishna More College, Pune

1st Aug. 2017 — 30th April 2019 - April 2019, Pune

- · Lecturer of Financial Accounts and Organization Skill Development..
- Designed and delivered comprehensive curriculum for Financial Accounts and Organization Skill Development, achieving a 95% student pass rate and enhancing student engagement through interactive learning modules.
- · contributing to the advancement of knowledge in financial accounting and attracting scholarly attention to the college.

Associate Team Member

SLK Global Solution Ltd. Pune

16th June 2014 — 15th Oct. 2015- October 2015, Pune

- · Worked in Fraud and Dispute Process (Cheque Services).
- · Solved queries of Account holders of Fifth Third Bank, USA
- · Managed Accounts such as Pass Debit or credit entries of customers Accounts.
- · Managed offsetting Account of US customers..
- Administered transaction processing for approximately 100 accounts daily, enhancing accuracy by 15% through rigorous cross-checking and error rectification procedures.
- Implemented process improvements in the Fraud and Dispute Process, achieving a 20% reduction in processing time by streamlining workflow operations and employing automated tools for repetitive tasks.

EDUCATION

B.Com

North Maharashtra University Jalgaon \cdot 2014 \cdot 72%

S.S.C

Nashik Board • 2009 • 59.70%

M.Com

Pune University • 2016 • 63%

 $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Advanced Accounting and Taxation.

H.S.C

Nashik Board • 2011 • 64.83%

CERTIFICATIONS

SAP FICO

DIGICATION INSTITUTE DELHI · 2021

 $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Certification in SAP FICO from Digication Institute Delhi..

English Typing

Typing Institute • 2017

• English Typing 30 WPM.

Tally ERP 9

Tally • 2014

· Certification in Tally ERP 9..

SKILLS

Accounting Operations, Bank/Vendor Reconciliation

Coordination, Organizational skills, SAP FICO

Soft Skills: Communication, Problem solving, Decision Making

Soft Skills: Communication Soft Skills: Confidently

English, Hindi, Marathi

English Typing 30 WPM

SAP, SAP FICO, Tally ERP 9